Today we all Sahaja Yogis are standing on the brink of the ocean,
今天 我们所有霎哈嘉瑜伽士 都站在海洋的边缘
ocean of humanity,
人类的海洋
where we have to face the problems of human beings.
我们必须面对人类的问题
Otherwise, in the nature there are no problems, they are all already solved.
除此之外 在自然界中没有问题 它们都已经解决了
So one has to understand that
所以我们必须明白这一点
it’s not just a movement of few people, chosen people,
这不仅仅是一场由少数人 被选中的人组成的运动
just to achieve Self-realisation,
只是为了实现自觉
but it’s a big revolution
而是一场巨大的革命
which has to bring forth the beauties of human beings,
它必须展现人类的美
the glories of human beings, the proof of divinity,
人类的荣耀 神性的证明
of divine power and of God Almighty.
神圣的力量和全能的上帝
We have to now face that multitude of people
我们现在必须面对大众
who are absolutely ignorant compared to you,
他们比起你们简直一无所知
who have not known the knowledge of God,
他们不了解神的知识
who are either lost into the darkness of ignorance
他们要么迷失在无知的黑暗中
or are burning in the fire of ego.
或者在自我的火焰中燃烧
We have to transform this world into a new world,
我们得把这个世界变成一个新的世界
a beautiful world which you all are enjoying,
一个你们都在享受的美丽世界
to establish it, to be established on this earth,
建立它 建立在这个地球上
for which we have to prepare ourselves.
为此 我们必须做好准备
So far Sahaj Yoga means blessings;
到目前为止 霎哈嘉瑜伽意味着祝福
if somebody is less blessed they ask Me questions, “How is it, Mother,
如果有人不那么受祝福 他们会问我 母亲 怎么会这样
we haven’t got this when we are praying to You?
当我向你祈祷 我怎么没有得到呢
Why did it not work out?
为什么不灵呢
It should have happened, after all we are worshipping You,
这应该发生啊 毕竟我们是在崇拜你
so how is it that my son did not get the job?”
那么 我儿子怎么没有得到这份工作呢
So, I mean, as if it’s sort of a, some debts have to be paid
所以 我的意思是 好像这有点像
to all the Sahaja Yogis by Sahaj Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽必须偿还债务给 所有的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
That sort of an attitude has been, so far, towards Sahaj Yog.
到目前为止 这一直是对待霎哈嘉瑜伽的态度
Of, not all of you, I must say,
我必须说 不是你们所有人
but in the minds there’s lurking always, a desire to know
但在头脑中 总是潜伏着一种了解的渴望
why, when we are Sahaj Yogis, why should it happen to us.
为什么 当我们是霎哈嘉瑜伽士时 为什么它会发生在我们身上
You’ve seen that God has blessed you.
你已经看到上帝祝福了你
Some people had very miserable married life,
有些人的婚姻生活非常悲惨
they couldn’t understand why they had to have a miserable married life.
他们不明白 为什么他们不得不过着痛苦的婚姻生活
Some had some misfortunes
有些人有一些不幸
and some had some diseases also after coming to Sahaj Yoga.
有些人在来到霎哈嘉瑜伽后也得了一些病
So there has to be understanding that Sahaj Yoga is
因此 必须理解霎哈嘉瑜伽是
for correcting your life, for putting you on solid basis,
纠正你的生活 让你站稳脚跟
on proper foundations to make you great people.
在适当的基础上 使你们成为了不起的人
As if it gets you immuned to all these mishappenings,
仿佛它让你对所有这些不幸的事件 具有免疫力
with blessings of course, so you don’t feel the effects
当然因为祝福 所以你不太感觉到那些不幸的影响
of those misfortunes so much as you would normally feel.
不会像你通常所感受到的那样
This creates beautiful human beings out of you.
这将为你们创造出美丽的人类
Some people have hankering after money;
有些人渴望金钱
some people think they can make money by coming to Sahaj Yoga;
有些人认为他们来霎哈嘉瑜伽可以赚钱
some people think they will become leaders or some think they will have fame,
有些人认为他们会成为领导者 有些人认为他们会有名气
some think that they will achieve a kind of a very dominant position;
有些人认为他们将获得一种非常优越的地位
and some think that they can befool Me also.
有些人认为他们也能骗过我
It’s high time we realise that Sahaj Yoga is not for this.
现在是我们意识到 霎哈嘉瑜伽不是为了这些的时候了
Sahaj Yoga is for making you the wisest person,
霎哈嘉瑜伽是为了让你成为最有智慧的人
the sanest person, the most generous and the most confident person in the world,
成为世界上最明智的人 最慷慨 最自信的人
because you have to fight,
因为你们不得不战斗
you have to fight the dark ignorance of Kali Yuga,
你们必须与 Kali Yuga （黑暗期）的黑暗无知作斗争
of ages which is precipitated and today we see all the bad effects of it.
世世代代所沉淀的无知 今天我们看到了它的所有不良影响
Whatever you may call it, you may call it the fanaticism,
无论你怎么称呼它 你可以称它为狂热
you may call it the atheism, any isms of any kinds,
你可以称它为无神论 各种各样的主义
and all these human projections which have created
以及所有这些人类的投射所创造的
all those artificial webs have to be broken.
所有这些人造的网都必须被打破
But human beings, on the whole, believe that these artificial webs are real.
但总的来说 人类相信这些人造的网是真实的
So to break that,
所以要打破它们
you have to be also be careful that you don’t break the human beings.
你也必须小心 不要破坏人类
While you are breaking their false faiths,
当你打破他们的错误信仰时
you have to remember that those people who are carrying those false faiths
你必须记住 那些背负着错误信仰的人
are the ones who have to achieve Self-realisation.
是必须获得自觉的人
It’s a very delicate work, it’s a very hard work, it’s a very harsh work
这是一项非常精细的工作 一项非常艰苦的工作
but it is the most detached work.
但它是最需要抽离的工作
And when we realise that we are so important,
当我们意识到自己是如此重要时
that God has blessed us with this peace,
上帝赐予了我们这平安
with this understanding, with these powers -
凭着这种理解 凭着这些力量
it’s not only for our own gain,
这不仅仅是为了我们自己的利益
because God is not only for you, He is for the whole world.
因为上帝不仅是为了你 他是为了全世界
So we have to utilise them, we have to spread them,
所以我们必须利用它们 我们必须传播它们
work it out at every level; we have to become dynamic about it.
在各个层面上解决问题 我们必须对此充满活力
But the most important thing is the responsibility
但最重要的是责任
of Sahaj Yoga we have to take.
我们必须承担霎哈嘉瑜伽的责任
We are Sahaj Yogis and we are responsible for Sahaj Yoga.
我们是霎哈嘉瑜伽士 我们负责霎哈嘉瑜伽
What have we done for Sahaj Yoga?
我们为霎哈嘉瑜伽做了什么
We looked after our family, our children, our jobs,
我们照顾我们的家庭 孩子 工作
our this, our that, motorcars, our horses, our dogs, our cats.
我们的这个 我们的那个 我们的汽车 我们的马 我们的狗 我们的猫
But who is responsible for Sahaj Yoga?
但是谁来负责霎哈嘉瑜伽呢
When it comes to that point, we are responsible
当涉及到这一点时 我们要负责
of Sahaj Yoga, then it works out.
霎哈嘉瑜伽 然后问题就解决了
But there is a deliberate action also of the negative forces.
但是 负面力量也有蓄意的行动
And this negativity is acting through ignorant people who believe,
而这种负面是通过无知的人行事
who believe that they are right.
这些人相信自己是对的
They don’t know what is waiting for their destruction there.
他们不知道那里等待着他们的将是 怎样的毁灭
Specially among our young people you’ll find
特别是在我们的年轻人中 您会发现
they just join any party, join any club,
他们只是加入一些党派 加入一些俱乐部
join any methods, any trend, anything,
参与一些研究方法 一些潮流 任何东西
just because they have no understanding as to what they have to be.
只是因为他们不了解自己必须成为什么
They have to be the Spirit.
他们必须成为灵
I asked the other day a president of a young organisation,
前几天 我问一个年轻组织的主席
“What is your policy?” He said, “We have no policy.”
你的原则是什么 他说 我们没有原则
They started looking here and there, [and] said, “We have no policy.”
他们开始四处寻找 (然后)说 我们没有原则
I was amazed that they have no policy.
我很惊讶他们没有原则
“No, whatever our leaders say, we do it.”
没有 我们的领导人说什么 我们就做什么
So to get people out of this kind of slavery
因此 要让人们摆脱这种奴役
that they have no brains of their own, they can’t use their own understanding,
他们没有自己的脑子 他们不能利用自己的理解
they have to become the Spirit.
他们必须成为灵
Shivaji who was a great Atma Sakshatkari, a realised soul,
Shivaji 是一位伟大的 Atma Sakshatkari 一个自觉的灵魂
for the future he has given the message.
为了未来 他已经传达了这个信息
He said, “Svadharma jagwawa,” means enlighten your dharma of Spirit.
他说 Svadharma jagwawa 意思是启迪你灵性的正法
“Svadharma,” the Spirit has to be enlightened.
Svadharma 灵必须得到启蒙
Everybody has said that. I’m specially quoting him
每个人都这么说过 我特别引用了他的话
because he comes from Maharashtra; apart from that he was a political head.
因为他来自马哈拉施特拉邦 除此之外 他还是一位政治领袖
Though he was a political head but because he was a realised soul,
虽然他是一个政治首脑 但因为他是一个自觉的灵
he said that your Spirit should be awakened.
他说你的灵应该被唤醒
He didn’t talk of all other nonsensical things.
他没有谈论所有其他荒谬的事情
And he knew that unless and until the Spirit is awakened,
他知道 除非灵被唤醒
people will be doing all kinds of wrong things.
人们会做各种错误的事情
And that is why today we find all over the world
这就是为什么今天我们在世界各地都能发现
the mess in which all political parties,
所有政党都陷入了混乱
all economic endeavours, all military endeavours have fallen into.
所有经济上的努力 所有军事上的努力都陷入了困境
So, it is for us to take over and to show them what is an integrated life,
所以 我们应该接手 并向他们展示什么是整合的生活
and what is the strength of a human being.
以及一个人的力量是什么
Because this Shakti is within everyone.
因为这个力量 Shakti 存在于每个人的内在
Just praying to Shakti, just talking about Shakti, it doesn’t act.
只是向 Shakti 祈祷 只是谈论 Shakti 它不会起作用
But this divine Shakti has to act, and act through you people.
但是这个神圣的 Shakti 必须行动 并通过你们这些人行动
Just try to realise
试着去意识到
that within these few years how much knowledge you have got,
在这几年里 你获得了多少知识
how much you know, how deeply you know.
你知道多少 你知道得有多深入
You are not just passing slogans or talking, you know -
你不只是在传递口号或说话
but you know it, you know what it is.
而是你知道它 你了解它是什么
I don’t think I have attended to each one of you individually,
我认为我没有单独照顾你们每一个人
but through your Spirit only you have come to know
但只有通过你的灵 你才能知道
all the knowledge about yourself and knowledge about others.
所有关于你自己的知识 以及关于他人的知识
You didn’t have to go to any library, you didn’t have to go to any university.
你不必去任何图书馆 也不必上任何大学
All the saints never went,
所有的圣人都没有去过
none of the saints went to any university or read any books,
没有一个圣人上过任何大学 也没有读过什么书
but how knowledgeable they were, because they were the Spirit.
但他们是多么博学 因为他们是灵
So the first and foremost responsibility of a Sahaj Yogi
因此 霎哈嘉瑜伽士今天的首要责任是 要成为灵
on this day is to be the Spirit, on the day when we are celebrating
在我们庆祝基督生日这一天成为灵
the birthday of Christ, who was the Spirit.
因为基督耶稣就是灵
So, this is our greatest responsibility first to see that,
所以 这是我们最大的责任 首先要看到
“Are we the Spirit, or we are this body, this mind, this ego? What are we?”
我们是灵 还是我们是这个身体 这个思想 这个自我 我们是什么
If you have achieved that state,
如果您已达到那个状态
then you are, as they call in Marathi, samarthya,
那么你就是他们在马拉地语中所说的 samarthya
means, you are equal to your name; that you are the Spirit.
意思是名符其实 你就是灵
If you cannot achieve that,
如果你无法做到这一点
then you are a half-baked Sahaj Yogi, not yet done.
那么你是一个半吊子的霎哈嘉瑜伽士 还没有成为
As you know, we have no organisations, no memberships, nothing.
如你所知 我们没有组织 没有会员 什么都没有
But we have one thing, that we know we are realised souls,
但我们有一件事 那就是我们知道自己是自觉的灵
that we know more than all others know, and that we are not proud of it.
我们知道的比其他人都多 而且我们并不为此骄傲
We are very humble people.
我们是非常谦逊的人
But this humility should not become a stagnation or a lethargy within us that,
但这种谦卑不应该变成 我们内在的停滞或死气沉沉
“Now we are realised souls, let us sit on a tree and have our blessings.”
现在我们是自觉的灵魂 让我们坐在树上 享受我们的祝福
You have to get to the roots
你必须找到根源
and you all have to work it out on your level.
你们都必须根据自己的水平解决这个问题
But first get rid of your own personal problems,
但先去除你自己的个人问题
all petty things that you have.
你自己的所有琐事
When we talk of sacrifice, as you know,
正如我们所知 当我们谈论牺牲时
in Sahaj Yoga I have not known what sacrifice people have done.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽 我不知道人们做了什么牺牲
You have to sacrifice your ego,
你必须牺牲你的自我
which is a headache to you and to Me.
这让你和我都头疼
And you have to sacrifice your conditioning,
而且你得牺牲你的思想制约
only two things, left and right.
只有这两件事 左和右
And that can be achieved and many have achieved [it],
这是可以达到的 而且许多人已经实现了 (它)
but now put that detached personality to a test.
但现在要考验抽离的个性
And then, once you are sure that you are detached,
然后 一旦你确定你是抽离的
then employ your energy in doing
然后把你的精力用在
constructive improvement of this whole world.
建设性地改善整个世界
It will work out for poverty, it will work out for politics,
它将会解决贫困问题 也会解决政治问题
it will work out for economics, it will work out for every field of life.
它将解决经济问题 它将解决生活每个领域的问题
Sahaj Yoga is the only solution because in this human beings are transformed.
霎哈嘉瑜伽是唯一的解决方案 因为人类因此得到了转化
It’s not like this, that one person changes the address
不是像一个人改了地址
or the badge that he is wearing, and he becomes something else.
或者换了他戴的徽章 他就变成了其他东西
Or from church to temple and temple to church.
或者从一个教堂到另一个寺庙 从一个寺庙到另一个教堂
It’s something within that transforms you, makes you knowledgeable.
而是某种内在的东西转化了你 让你变得知识渊博
So you are already Sat Chit Ananda; because you know the truth,
所以你已经是 Sat真理 Chit意识 Ananda喜乐 因为你知道了真理
you are in joy and your attention is enlightened.
你在喜乐之中 而你的注意力得到了启发
With all this that you have, what are we to do now?
拥有了你所拥有的一切 我们现在该怎么做
If you enlighten the light, it automatically knows
如果你启迪了光 它自动就会知道
that it has to give the light.
它必须给予光明
In the same way, all the Sahaj Yogis have to take the responsibility
同样 所有的霎哈嘉瑜伽士都必须承担责任
for this great war we have started.
为了这场我们已经开始的伟大战争
It’s not the war with swords or with atomic energies,
这不是用刀剑或原子能的战争
because they are all destructive.
因为它们都是破坏性的
This is the war against all the destructive powers
这是对抗所有破坏性力量的战争
through the power of love which is constructive,
通过建设性的爱的力量
which constructs human beings, which constructs societies,
它构建了人类 构建了社会
which constructs countries and the whole world.
它构建了国家和整个世界
That is your own
那是你自己的
and also this decision has to be your own.
而且这个决定必须是你自己的
Even if I give big lectures and say things,
即使我长篇大论和发表演讲
it may not have any effect whatsoever on you.
它可能对你没有任何影响
It might be just wasted,
它可能只是被浪费了
if you haven’t got the capacity to imbibe what I am saying,
如果你没有能力吸收我所说的
so important, so imminent.
如此重要 如此迫在眉睫
Now give up all the worries you have about
现在放弃你所有的烦恼
your small, small, little, little things of your family,
你家里的小事 琐事
of your work, your factories,
你的工作 你的工厂
of your business, of your official positions
您的业务 您的官职
and just know that everything has to go through Sahaj Yoga.
只要知道一切都必须通过霎哈嘉瑜伽来成就
Even the cooking I do, I do it through Sahaj.
甚至我做的饭 也是通过霎哈嘉来做的
If the fire is not working, just put your hands to the fire, it becomes all right.
如果火不工作 只需将手放在火上就可以了
If the rice is not cooking, put your hands to the rice, it cooks.
如果米饭没有煮熟 将手放在米饭上 米饭就会煮熟
Anything going wrong anywhere, you can use your vibrations.
任何地方出现任何问题 你都可以使用自己的生命能量
But I don’t know what to use to make you feel responsible for Sahaj Yoga,
但我不知道该用什么 来让你觉得自己对霎哈嘉瑜伽负责
that now we’ve got such a great thing with us
现在我们有了这么棒的东西
and what are we going to do about it.
那么我们将要为此做些什么